Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Review Board Records, 1947-1976, 1987-1995 RL.00745
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Review Board records
1947-1976, 1987-1995
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.00745
19.0 Linear Feet
circa 10,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted: Photocopying from the Review Board Records is prohibited.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Review Board Records were transferred to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) in 1987. Processing of this collection was supported in part by gifts from the J. Walter Thompson Company Fund and the John and Kelly Hartman Foundation.
Historical Note
The Review Board, an advisory system began informally in 1942 as the Plans Board, when James Webb Young and Walter O'Meara headed the Creative Department. In 1956 JWT instituted the Review Board as a trans-departmental entity with written procedures and a Review Board Secretary.
In the years 1964 to 1969, Review Board functions were divided into a Plans Board, which reviewed the account team's recommended strategy (i.e., the basic proposition the advertising should made to consumers), and a Creative Review Board, which evaluated proposals for the implementation and execution of the advertising strategy.
Collection Overview
The Review Board Records, J. Walter Thompson Company's New York Office's primary mechanism for controlling the quality of its services, span the years 1947 and 1953-1976 (bulk 1956-1974). Senior-level creative, account, and management personnel composed the Review Board. It provided guidance to account teams, which were assigned to manage advertising for particular clients, and ensured that client campaigns reflected the cumulative wisdom of the Company's most experienced employees. Frequent changes in the Review Board system make a brief description of its operations impossible, but generally, five to eight creative, account, and management personnel comprised a Review Board for each advertising account. Clients' different brands might have a separate Review Board for each product. Individual Review Board members usually had responsibility for a dozen or more accounts. The procedures called for meetings at least once a year and every time account representatives considered a major campaign. The records consist of meeting minutes, correspondence, memoranda, and reports. Clients represented include Lever Brothers, Liggett and Myers, Scott Paper Company, Warner-Lambert, Standard Brands, Ford Motor Company, Chesebrough-Ponds, Eastman Kodak and a number of others.
The Procedures Series documents the organization and format of the Review Board over time. Also reflected is a widely held perception that the Review Board system was itself in need of some quality control. Confusion over time about the Board's scope and purpose led to numerous attempts at explaining and refining its procedures. The series is organized into the following subseries: Reports, Domestic Correspondence, International Correspondence, and Chronologies and Lists.
The Meetings Series documents the activities of the Review Board, focusing on advertising campaign strategies for JWT's clients. It forms the bulk of the collection.
Advertising agencies; Advertising -- Management; Scott Paper Company; Standard Brands Incorporated; Warner-Lambert Company; Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company; Ford Motor Company; Eastman Kodak Company; Chesebrough-Pond's.; Lever Brothers Company; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; J. Walter Thompson Company
- Procedures Series, 1954-1975.
  Scope and Contents note
  The Procedures Series contains reports, correspondence, and file lists relating to the Review Board's format, staff assignments, and meeting dates. It also contains correspondence, file lists, and a report relating to the semi-annual Account Summaries that account teams prepared for Review Board members.
  - Reports Subseries, 1954-1975.
    Reports include documents that outline proper Review Board procedures and others that recommend changes in existing guidelines. This subseries also contains a 1967 report on format revisions for the semi-annual Account Summaries.
    Arrangement note
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Reports, 1954, 1956-1962, 1964-1975, 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Domestic Correspondence Subseries, 1956-1974.
    The Domestic Correspondence files contain correspondence and memoranda about procedural problems, member assignment notices, meeting schedules, and specifications for a remodeled meeting room. Also included are memoranda to account supervisors regarding overdue Account Summaries.
    Arranged chronologically with some overlapping dates.
    - Domestic Correspondence, 1956-1958, 1960-1961, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Domestic Correspondence, 1961-1974, 11 folders (Box 2)
    - Domestic Correspondence, 1968-1972, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - International Correspondence Subseries, 1964-1969.
    International Correspondence includes information about the implementation of Review Board meetings in some of JWT's international offices, particularly those in Great Britain, Japan, and Brazil.
    - International Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 3)
  - Chronologies and Lists Subseries, 1964-1976.
    The Chronologies and Lists files contain two kinds of information. First, a chronological list records the dates of all Review Board meetings, the names of persons present, and brief, two or three word descriptions of the topic(s) discussed. This chronological record may be a useful resource for determining which client accounts were attracting the greatest attention from senior level personnel. Second, this subseries contains an annual list of the Account Summaries on file with the Review Board Secretary.
    Arranged chronologically within each category.
    - Chronologies and Lists, 1964-1976, 5 folders (Box 3)
- Meetings Series, 1950-1974.
  The Meetings Series contains minutes, Account Summaries, and memoranda pertaining to Review Board meetings. Meeting minutes and related materials (such as background memoranda and reports) comprise the bulk of the records. The minutes were recorded by the Review Board Secretary (or in some cases a Review Board member), and they generally include a list of Review Board members, a statement of the meeting's purpose, up-to-date marketing information, analysis of the advertising "proposition" (a capsule statement of what consumers should hope to gain from purchasing client's product), and final conclusions and recommendations. In some cases the writer records discussions verbatim, providing further insight into the personalities and groups processes involved (see files for Pan-American Airlines, 1959-1960; Chesebrough-Ponds, 1957-1959). There are no Review Board meetings minutes for 1966-1968.
  Account Summaries often were submitted prior to Review Board meetings, allowing them to function like a background memorandum for particular meetings. Otherwise, they provided Review Board members with an accessible, systematic examination of the status of each account. The Account Summary format changed in 1967, but generally it contained the following information: financial marketing figures for the past five years, a summary of market conditions for the client's product, a summary of advertising (current objectives and expenditures), and a frank assessment of problems and prospects for the account.
  Some folders in the Meeting Records Series are labeled "John Monsarrat" because they contain documents from his personal files. He was a member of some Review Boards, chairperson of several others, and the JWT executive responsible for the Review Board system in its entirety from 1960 to 1965. His files contain memoranda and meeting minutes that would otherwise be missing from the Review Board Records.
  Arranged alphabetically by client.
  - Alberto-Culver, Minutes, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Alcan Aluminum Corp.
    - Summaries, 1961-1974 (Box 3)
    - Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Aluminum Limited, Minutes, 1953-1964, 1966, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - American Bankers Association, Minutes, 1956 (Box 4)
  - American Electric Power Service Corp.
    - Summaries, 1961-1966 (Box 4)
    - Minutes, 1956-1962, 1964 (Box 4)
  - American Film Theatre, Summaries, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - American Gas Association
    - Summaries, 1967-1974 (Box 4)
    - Minutes, 1971-1973, 5 folders (Box 4)
  - American Gas Association, Minutes, 1974 (Box 5)
  - American Home Products
    - Summaries (Whitehall Labs), 1965-1967 (Box 5)
    - Minutes, 1965 (Box 5)
  - American Hospital Association, Summaries, 1974 (Box 5)
  - American Machine Foundry Co., Summaries, 1967-1968 (Box 5)
  - American Petroleum Institute
    - Summaries, 1963-1970 (Box 5)
    - Minutes, 1961-1963, 1965 (Box 5)
  - American Red Cross, Minutes, 1958-1963 (Box 5)
  - Amprop Inc.
    - Summaries, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Minutes, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Aquascutum, Ltd., Minutes, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Aspen Systems Corp., Summaries, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Association of Playing Card Manufacturers, Minutes, 1953-1954, 1956-1960, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Bausch and Lomb
    - Summaries, 1969-1974 (Box 5)
    - Minutes, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Beecham Products (formerly H.F. Ritchie Co.)
    - Summaries, 1961-1962 (Box 5)
    - Minutes
      - Eno Antacid, 1959-1962 (Box 5)
      - Scotts Emulsion, 1956-1961 (Box 5)
  - Blue Cross/Blue Shield
    - Summaries
      - Associated Hospital Service of New York, 1962-1974 (Box 5)
      - Blue Cross National Account, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
      - Group Hospitalization and Medical Service of Washington DC, 1966-1974 (Box 5)
      - North Carolina BC/BS Inc., 1965-1974 (Box 5)
      - United Medical Service of New York, 1961-1972 (Box 5)
  - Blue Cross/Blue Shield (Box 6)
    - Minutes, 1956-1963, 1972, 1974, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Boyle-Midway, Minutes, 1957-1959 (Box 6)
  - Brillo Manufacturing Co.
    - Summaries
      - Brillons, 1966 (Box 6)
      - Dobie, 1963-1967 (Box 6)
      - Industrial/Institutional products, 1966-1967 (Box 6)
      - Paddy soap pads, 1966 (Box 6)
      - Purex, Brillo soap pads, 1961-1967 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, 1953-1964, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Buitoni, Minutes, 1955-1956 (Box 6)
  - Burlington Industries, Minutes, 1956-1957 (Box 6)
  - Burroughs International, Minutes, 1957-1959 (Box 6)
  - Burry Biscuit Co.
    - Summaries, 1966-1968 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Champion Spark Plug Co., Summaries, 1962-1974, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Champion Spark Plug Co., Minutes, 1956-1963, 1973, 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's
    - Summaries
      - Angel Skin Hand Lotion, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
      - Creams, 1961-1970 (Box 7)
      - Cutex Lipstick, 1965-1966 (Box 7)
      - Cutex Nail Polish, 1963-1966 (Box 7)
      - Dreamflower Talc, 1965-1970 (Box 7)
      - Fresh Start, 1965-1970 (Box 7)
      - Make-ups, 1961-1966 (Box 7)
      - Pond's Beauty Wash, 1968 (Box 7)
      - Prince Matchabelli, 1961-1967 (Box 7)
    - Minutes
      - 1947, 1953-1965, 5 folders (Box 7)
      - Angel Face, 1961-1963 (Box 7)
      - Dreamflower Talc, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's (Box 8)
    - Minutes
      - Perfume, 1960-1963 (Box 8)
      - Polyderm, 1961-1963 (Box 8)
      - Prince Matchabelli, 1959-1963 (Box 8)
      - Teen-Age Gel, 1962 (Box 8)
      - John Monsarrat, 1960-1962 (Box 8)
  - Chunky Chocolate Corp.
    - Summaries, 1962-1967 (Box 8)
    - Minutes, 1961-1963 (Box 8)
  - Church and Dwight, Minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 8)
  - Ciba Pharmaceuticals, Minutes, 1957 (Box 8)
  - Citizens and Southern National Bank, Summaries, 1970-1972 (Box 8)
  - CNA Financial Corp.
    - Summaries, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
    - Minutes, 1971, 1973, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Congoleum
    - Summaries, 1962-1974 (Box 8)
    - Minutes, 1961-1964, 1966-1967, 1970, 1974, 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Crocker-Citizens Bank, Minutes, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Crompton-Richmond, Minutes, 1956-1957 (Box 8)
  - Custom Farms, Inc., Minutes, 1961 (Box 8)
  - Dean Witter, Minutes, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Devoe and Reynolds, Minutes, 1957 (Box 8)
  - Douglas Aircraft Co., Summaries, 1961-1966 (Box 8)
  - Douglas Aircraft Co. (Box 9)
    - Minutes
      - 1955-1963, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - John Monsarrat, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Francis I. DuPont and Co.
    - Summaries, 1961-1963 (Box 9)
    - Minutes, 1954-1962 (Box 9)
  - Eastman Chemical Products, Minutes, 1972-1973, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Eastman Kodak Co.
    - Summaries, 1961-1965
      - Business Systems, 1964-1974 (Box 9)
      - Chemicals, 1974 (Box 9)
      - Consumer Markets, 1964-1974 (Box 9a)
      - Corporate, 1969-1970 (Box 9a)
      - Customer Equipment, 1972-1974 (Box 9a)
      - Infrared and College Recruitment, 1964-1967 (Box 9a)
      - International Photographic Division, 1964-1974 (Box 9a)
      - Kodel Fiberfill, 1972-1974 (Box 9a)
      - Kodel for Carpeting, 1974 (Box 9a)
      - Kodel Polyester, 1971-1973 (Box 9a)
      - Kodel Staple/Filament, 1971-1974 (Box 9a)
  - Eastman Kodak Co. (Box 10)
    - Summaries
      - Motion Picture and Audio Visual Markets Division, 1964-1974 (Box 10)
      - Plastics, 1964-1974 (Box 10)
      - Premium Products, 1964-1965 (Box 10)
      - Professional and Finishing, 1966-1974 (Box 10)
      - Radiography, 1964-1974 (Box 10)
    - Minutes, 1954-1964, 10 folders (Box 10)
    - Minutes, 1964-1972 (Box 10a)
  - Eastman Kodak Co. (Box 11)
    - Minutes
      - 1973 (Box 11)
      - Motion Picture and Audio Visual, 1973 (Box 11)
      - Radiography, 1973 (Box 11)
      - John Monsarrat, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Eaton Corp.
    - Summaries, 1970-1974 (Box 11)
    - Minutes, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Eaton, Yale and Towne, Minutes, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Thomas A. Edison Industries, Inc.
    - Summaries, 1961-1970 (Box 11)
    - Minutes, 1956, 1964 (Box 11)
  - Farrell Lines, Minutes, 1956-1957 (Box 11)
  - Fieldcrest Mills, Minutes, 1956-1957 (Box 11)
  - Firestone Tire and Rubber
    - Summaries
      - Diversified Products, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
      - Farm and Truck Tires, 1969-1971 (Box 11)
      - Passenger Tires, 1969-1971 (Box 11)
    - Minutes, 1969, 1971, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - First National City Bank
    - Summaries
      - Charge Service, 1967-1971 (Box 11)
      - Investment Management, 1967-1971 (Box 11)
      - Travelers Checks, 1966-1971 (Box 11)
  - Ford
    - Summaries, Ford Dealers (FDA)
      - Buffalo, 1973-1974 (Box 11)
      - New England, 1973-1974 (Box 11)
      - Philadelphia, 1973-1974 (Box 11)
      - Pittsburgh, 1973-1974 (Box 11)
      - Washington D.C., 1973-1974 (Box 11)
    - Minutes, 1963 (Box 11)
  - Ford (Box 12)
    - Minutes
      - 1970-1972 (Box 12)
      - Body Quality, 1959-1961 (Box 12)
      - Ford of Canada, 1959, 1961 (Box 12)
      - Cars, 1954-1962, 6 folders (Box 12)
      - Dealers (FDA), 1957-1963, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - English and German Lines, 1957-1958 (Box 12)
      - Falcon, 1959-1960 (Box 12)
      - International, 1955-1961, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Ford (Box 13)
    - Minutes
      - International, 1962-1964, 1966 (Box 13)
      - Parts and Service, 1960-1962 (Box 13)
      - Redwing, 1962 (Box 13)
      - Research, 1961 (Box 13)
      - Thunderbird, 1957-1960, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Trucks, 1953-1964, 5 folders (Box 13)
      - Used Cars, 1959 (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous, 1953-1956, 1959-1960, 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Ford (Box 14)
    - Minutes
      - Miscellaneous, 1961-1962 (Box 14)
      - John Monsarrat, 1964-1965 (Box 14)
  - Foundation for Commercial Banks
    - Summaries, 1961-1962 (Box 14)
    - Minutes, 1955-1956, 1958-1962, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Franklin State Bank, Summaries, 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - R.T. French Co.
    - Summaries
      - Bel-Air Croutons, 1973-1974 (Box 14)
      - Cattlemen's Barbeque Sauce, 1961, 1966 (Box 14)
      - Dry Sauce and Gravy Mixes, 1962-1974 (Box 14)
      - Forman's Piccalilli and Pickles, 1961-1964 (Box 14)
      - Justrite Fire Starters, 1963-1964 (Box 14)
      - Military Markets, 1963-1966 (Box 14)
      - Mustards, 1961-1974 (Box 14)
      - Pet Bird Food, 1963-1964 (Box 14)
      - Potato Products, 1961-1974 (Box 14)
      - Spices and Extracts, 1962-1964 (Box 14)
      - Worcestershire Sauce, 1961-1974 (Box 14)
    - Minutes, 1954, 1956-1959, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - R.T. French Co. (Box 15)
    - Minutes, 1959-1964, 1966, 1973, 4 folders
      - Forman's Piccalilli, 1961 (Box 15)
      - Spices and Extracts, 1961 (Box 15)
      - Worcestershire Sauce, 1961-1962 (Box 15)
      - John Monsarrat, 1964 (Box 15)
  - General Wine and Spirits, Minutes, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Gift America, Summaries, 1972-1974 (Box 15)
  - Gillette
    - Summaries
      - Cricket Disposable Lighter, 1972 (Box 15)
      - Gillette Lady Sure Touch, 1972 (Box 15)
      - Platinum-Plus Injector Blades, 1970-1971 (Box 15)
      - Platinum-Plus Razor Blades, 1969-1972 (Box 15)
    - Minutes, 1969-1971, 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Glamorence Products Corp., Summaries, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Goldman Sachs and Co. (Box 16)
    - Summaries, 1972-1974 (Box 16)
    - Minutes, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Good Humor Corp.
    - Summaries, 1964-1967 (Box 16)
    - Minutes, 1964 (Box 16)
  - Gorton Group
    - Summaries
      - 1966-1970 (Box 16)
      - Red-L Hors d'oeuvres, 1969-1970 (Box 16)
    - Minutes, 1966, 1969 (Box 16)
  - Harrison Executive Conference Centers, Summaries, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Helio Aircraft Corp., Summaries, 1967 (Box 16)
  - Holiday Inns
    - Summaries, 1972-1974 (Box 16)
    - Minutes, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Institute of Life Insurance
    - Summaries, 1961-1974 (Box 16)
    - Minutes, 1953-1963, 1965, 1973, 5 folders (Box 16)
  - Inter-Continental Hotels Corp.
    - Summaries, 1963-1974 (Box 16)
    - Minutes, 1963, 1970, 1972, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Irving Trust Co.
    - Summaries, 1961-1974 (Box 16)
    - Minutes, 1961-1963, 1969, 1971( 3 folders) (Box 16)
  - Irving Trust Co., Minutes, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Johns-Manville Corp., Minutes, 1956-1958 (Box 17)
  - Keep New York City Clean, Minutes, 1959-1960 (Box 17)
  - Kingsberry Homes
    - Summaries, 1962 (Box 17)
    - Minutes, 1958-1961 (Box 17)
  - Kraft Corp., Summaries, 1969-1970 (Box 17)
  - Labatt's Beer, Minutes, 1963 (Box 17)
  - Lever Brothers
    - Summaries
      - Close-Up Dentifrice, 1972-1974 (Box 17)
      - Dinner-Ready Products, 1962 (Box 17)
      - Drive Detergent, 1968-1974 (Box 17)
      - Handy Andy, 1961-1965 (Box 17)
      - Lever V Crystal Wax, 1963-1964 (Box 17)
      - Lux Bright Wash, 1965-1966 (Box 17)
      - Lux Liquid, 1961-1972 (Box 17)
      - Lux Toilet Soap, 1961-1972 (Box 17)
      - Mrs. Butterworth Syrup, 1961-1963 (Box 17)
      - Reward and Shield Deodorant Soap, 1969-1972 (Box 17)
      - Reward Liquid Cleaner, 1961 (Box 17)
      - Rinso, 1961-1972 (Box 17)
      - Shield Deodorants, 1961-1966 (Box 17)
      - Spry Shortening, 1961-1966 (Box 17)
      - Stripe Toothpaste, 1961-1966 (Box 17)
      - New Products, 1971-1974 (Box 17)
    - Minutes
      - 1960, 1964-1965, 1969, 1972, 4 folders (Box 17)
      - Canada, 1954-1958, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Lever Brothers (Box 18)
    - Minutes
      - Close-Up, 1973 (Box 18)
      - Crystal Wax, 1963 (Box 18)
      - Dinner-Redy, 1962 (Box 18)
      - Drive, 1973 (Box 18)
      - Handy Andy, 1961-1962 (Box 18)
      - Lux Flakes and Liquid, 1955-1957, 1959-1963, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Lux Liquid, 1963 (Box 18)
      - Lux Toilet Soap, 1955-1959, 1961-1964, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Rinso Blue, 1955-1963, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Shield Deodorant, 1960-1963 (Box 18)
      - Spry Shortening, 1961-1963 (Box 18)
      - Stripe Toothpaste, 1956-1958, 1961-1963, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Lever Brothers, Minutes, Syrup, 1960-1963, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Liebmann Breweries
    - Summaries, 1962-1963 (Box 19)
    - Minutes, Rheingold Beer, 1962-1963 (Box 19)
  - Liggett and Myers
    - Summaries
      - Adam, 1971-1973 (Box 19)
      - Chesterfield, 1962-1973 (Box 19)
      - Devon, 1964-1965 (Box 19)
      - Duke, 1963 (Box 19)
      - Eve, 1971-1973 (Box 19)
      - International, All Brands, 1967-1969 (Box 19)
      - Lark, 1963-1973 (Box 19)
      - L and M, 1962-1973 (Box 19)
      - Masterpiece Pipe Tobacco, 1963-1966 (Box 19)
      - Oasis, 1962 (Box 19)
      - Parkway, 1968 (Box 19)
      - Red Man Chewing Tobacco, 1963-1973 (Box 19)
      - Velvet and Granger Pipe Tobaccos, 1962-1966 (Box 19)
      - New Products, 1972 (Box 19)
    - Minutes, 1961-1962, 5 folders (Box 19)
  - Liggett and Myers, Minutes, 1962-1964, 1969, 1972, 6 folders (Box 20)
  - Eli Lilly and Co., Summaries, 1968-1969 (Box 20)
  - McGraw-Edison, Minutes, 1955-1963, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Massachusetts Mutual Life Insurance Co.
    - Summaries, 1963-1967 (Box 20)
    - Minutes, 1954-1963, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Mennen Co.
    - Summaries
      - Bath Talc, 1968 (Box 20)
      - Dry Anti-Perspirant, 1969-1970 (Box 20)
      - Pushbutton Deodorant, 1967-1969 (Box 20)
      - Skin Bracer, 1967-1970 (Box 20)
      - Sof' Stroke Shaving Cream, 1967-1970 (Box 20)
      - Spray Deodorant, 1967-1968 (Box 20)
    - Minutes, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Mentholatum Co.
    - Summaries
      - Deep Heating Rub, 1961-1971 (Box 20)
      - Mentholatum M.P.O., 1962-1967 (Box 20)
      - Nasal Mist, 1961-1963 (Box 20)
      - Ointment, 1961-1971 (Box 20)
  - Mentholatum Co., Minutes, 1958-1965, 3 folders (Box 21)
  - Miles Laboratories
    - Summaries
      - Alka-2, 1971-1974 (Box 21)
      - Bugs Bunny Chewable Vitamins, 1971-1972 (Box 21)
      - Clocks Chewable Vitamins, 1969-1972 (Box 21)
      - Flintstones Chewable Vitamins, 1970-1972 (Box 21)
      - One-A-Day Vitamins, 1968-1974 (Box 21)
      - Sungard, 1970-1971 (Box 21)
      - New products, 1973 (Box 21)
    - Minutes, 1969-1970, 1972-1973, 4 folders (Box 21)
  - Mobil International, Minutes, 1962 (Box 21)
  - Monroe Auto Equipment, Minutes, 1974 (Box 21)
  - National Association of Home Builders
    - Summaries, 1971-1974 (Box 21)
    - Minutes, 1970, 1972, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - National Association of Investment Companies, Minutes, 1956-1957 (Box 21)
  - National Car Rental System
    - Summaries, 1963 (Box 21)
    - Minutes, 1963 (Box 21)
  - National Education Association (NEA), Summaries, 1972-1974 (Box 21)
  - New Holland Machine Co. (Box 22)
    - Summaries, 1961-1974 (Box 22)
    - Minutes, 1956-1958, 1961-1963, 1965-1974, 5 folders (Box 22)
  - New York Central, Minutes, 1956-1958 (Box 22)
  - New York World's Fair
    - Summaries, 1961-1965 (Box 22)
    - Minutes, 1963 (Box 22)
  - Northeast Airlines
    - Summaries, 1961-1962 (Box 22)
    - Minutes, 1957-1961 (Box 22)
  - Oneida, Minutes, 1956-1957 (Box 22)
  - Owens-Illinois Glass Co.
    - Summaries, 1961 (Box 22)
    - Minutes
      - Container/Institutional, 1956, 1957-1960 (Box 22)
      - Libbey, 1954-1961 (Box 22)
      - Picture Tube Replacement, 1953-1956, 1958-1959, 2 folders (Box 22a)
  - Panagra
    - Summaries, 1961-1966 (Box 22a)
    - Minutes, John Monsarrat, 1964 (Box 22a)
  - Pan American
    - Summaries (Box 22a)
    - Business Jets, 1964-1970 (Box 22a)
    - Passenger and Cargo, 1961-1974 (Box 22a)
  - Pan American (Box 23)
    - Minutes
      - 1955-1964, 1966, 1969-1970, 7 folders (Box 23)
      - Overseas Division, 1960-1961 (Box 23)
      - John Monsarrat, 1964 (Box 23)
  - Pepsi Co. International
    - Summaries, 1970-1971 (Box 23)
    - Minutes, 1971 (Box 23)
  - Pharmacraft, Minutes, 1959 (Box 23)
  - Phillips Petroleum Co., Summaries, 1963-1966, 4 folders (Box 23)